<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="sys_metadata_link">
    <sys_metadata_link action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <directory>update</directory>
        <documentkey>a8c7ea532ff08590e0f497eef699b69c</documentkey>
        <payload>&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;&lt;record_update sys_domain="global" table="kb_knowledge"&gt;
    &lt;kb_knowledge action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE"&gt;
        &lt;active&gt;true&lt;/active&gt;
        &lt;article_type&gt;text&lt;/article_type&gt;
        &lt;author display_value="Ben Fisher"&gt;bf532351db8303002901de90cf96196d&lt;/author&gt;
        &lt;can_read_user_criteria/&gt;
        &lt;cannot_read_user_criteria/&gt;
        &lt;category/&gt;
        &lt;cmdb_ci/&gt;
        &lt;description/&gt;
        &lt;direct&gt;false&lt;/direct&gt;
        &lt;disable_commenting&gt;false&lt;/disable_commenting&gt;
        &lt;disable_suggesting&gt;false&lt;/disable_suggesting&gt;
        &lt;display_attachments&gt;false&lt;/display_attachments&gt;
        &lt;flagged&gt;false&lt;/flagged&gt;
        &lt;image/&gt;
        &lt;kb_category display_value="Conflict and Combat"&gt;62fcab012f94b010e0f497eef699b6fd&lt;/kb_category&gt;
        &lt;kb_knowledge_base display_value="Star Wars RPG"&gt;4a4a278d2f54b010e0f497eef699b694&lt;/kb_knowledge_base&gt;
        &lt;language&gt;en&lt;/language&gt;
        &lt;meta/&gt;
        &lt;meta_description&gt;Because SWRPG utilizes an abstract method of describing combat, movement is similarly described in broad&lt;/meta_description&gt;
        &lt;number&gt;KB0010067&lt;/number&gt;
        &lt;parent/&gt;
        &lt;published&gt;2022-01-07&lt;/published&gt;
        &lt;rating/&gt;
        &lt;retired/&gt;
        &lt;roles/&gt;
        &lt;short_description&gt;Maneuvers&lt;/short_description&gt;
        &lt;source/&gt;
        &lt;sys_class_name&gt;kb_knowledge&lt;/sys_class_name&gt;
        &lt;sys_created_by&gt;ben.fisher&lt;/sys_created_by&gt;
        &lt;sys_created_on&gt;2022-01-07 17:09:03&lt;/sys_created_on&gt;
        &lt;sys_domain&gt;global&lt;/sys_domain&gt;
        &lt;sys_domain_path&gt;/&lt;/sys_domain_path&gt;
        &lt;sys_id&gt;a8c7ea532ff08590e0f497eef699b69c&lt;/sys_id&gt;
        &lt;sys_mod_count&gt;3&lt;/sys_mod_count&gt;
        &lt;sys_updated_by&gt;ben.fisher&lt;/sys_updated_by&gt;
        &lt;sys_updated_on&gt;2022-01-07 18:29:48&lt;/sys_updated_on&gt;
        &lt;sys_view_count&gt;0&lt;/sys_view_count&gt;
        &lt;taxonomy_topic/&gt;
        &lt;text&gt;&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Because SWRPG utilizes an abstract method of describing combat, movement is similarly described in broad strokes. Characters often do far more than shoot their blasters in combat, including pulling out stimpacks to heal a wounded comrade, slicing through a computer to open a blast door, or scaling a wall to get an advantage on their opponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all undertakings require a check. These minor activities are known as maneuvers and cover a wide range of activities that any character can perform. They require an investment of time and effort on the character&amp;#39;s part, but are simple enough that there is no chance of failure when doing them. Technically, characters perform maneuvers during narrative gameplay as well as encounters. However, maneuvers are tracked and defined during encounters because characters are more limited in their time and efforts by the frantic pace of conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt;"&gt;MANEUVER LIMITATIONS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A character may perform one free maneuver on his turn. He may also perform a second maneuver by voluntarily suffering two points of strain. (Characters may also perform a second maneuver through a particularly successful skill check, or by other means listed elsewhere.) However, regardless of the source, a single character may not perform more than two maneuvers during his turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MANEUVERS OUTSIDE A CHARACTER&amp;#39;S TURN &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, a character may even be able to perform a maneuver when it is not his turn. A stormtrooper rolling horribly on a Stealth check to ambush a character may generate a number of failures on his check. The GM may decide that the blunder allows his would-be victim the opportunity to perform a maneuver, even though it is the stormtroopers turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any bonus maneuvers gained outside of a character&amp;#39;s turn do not count towards the aforementioned limit of two maneuvers a character may perform during his turn—specifically because it happens outside of the character&amp;#39;s turn. These additional maneuvers are generally awarded at the providence of the GM, and thus there is no hard and fast limit to the number of maneuvers that can be awarded in this manner. However, the GM would be wise to limit the number of out-of-turn maneuvers each character performs each round to one or two at most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12pt;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TYPES OF MANEUVERS &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of the maneuvers a character can perform during combat. Please note that this list is not exhaustive. The entire point of maneuvers is that they can cover any activity relatively easy to perform that still requires some amount of time and effort. While these maneuvers are deliberately general to cover as many options as possible, if a player comes up with something he wants his character to do that is not covered by this list, he should not dismiss the idea out of hand. Instead, he should explain what he&amp;#39;d like to accomplish to his GM, who can decide if it can realistically be performed in a single maneuver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some activities may also require multiple maneuvers to perform. Generally, these maneuvers must be performed sequentially, without being interrupted by the character performing other maneuvers or actions, for the task to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIM &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During combat, a character can use the Aim maneuver to steady a weapon or line up a hit before attacking, granting a bonus to his next combat check. A character only gains the benefit of aiming if he remains in his current position and does not perform any additional maneuvers or actions before his next combat check. Any damage that exceeds the character&amp;#39;s soak also negates the benefit of aiming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aiming provides the character with one of the two following bonuses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="list-style-position: inside;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gain a boost die on the next combat check. If the character spends two consecutive maneuvers aiming, he gains 2 boost dice on the next combat check.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Target a specific item carried by the target, or a specific part of the target. This could allow the character to attempt to strike or shoot a weapon from his opponent&amp;#39;s hand, for example, or target an opponent&amp;#39;s limb to cripple him. If the character spends one maneuver aiming to do this, his next combat check suffers 2 setback dice If he spends two consecutive maneuvers aiming, the combat check suffers 1 setback die instead.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASSIST&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performing the assist maneuver allows an engaged ally to add 1 boost die to his next check. Several characters can use the assist maneuver to add more bonus boost dice to the engaged ally&amp;#39;s next check. All awarded bonus dice must be used on the assisted character&amp;#39;s next turn, otherwise they are discarded. The Game Master should use his own discretion when allowing Players to assist one another. Some actions simply do not benefit from assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GUARDED STANCE &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A character can take a maneuver to assume a guarded stance, helping him defend against melee attacks. A character who performs this maneuver adds 1 setback die to any combat checks he makes until the end of his next turn. However, he also gains melee defense 1 until the end of his next turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTERACT WITH THE ENVIRONMENT &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often a single maneuver is enough to interact with the environment around a character. This is a broad category of possible interactions, such as opening a blast door, ducking behind a wall, pressing a specific button on a control panel, or grabbing a blaster off of the ground. The following are some more specifically designed examples of interacting with the environment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="list-style-position: inside;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving a large item&lt;/strong&gt;. Flipping over a table, shoving a barrel into a pursuer&amp;#39;s path, hefting a crate; all of these would take a maneuver to perform.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Opening or closing a door&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether an electronic blast door or a primitive door with latches and hinges, opening or closing it takes a maneuver.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking cover&lt;/strong&gt;. Ducking behind a door jam, crouching behind a crate, or peeking around a tree trunk; all of these allow the character to gain ranged defense 1 (and some cover can grant a ranged defense higher than 1 if particularly sturdy). It takes a maneuver to take cover, but once in cover, the character keeps the bonus unless the circumstances around him change so that he would no longer benefit from cover, or he moves out of cover.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MANAGE GEAR &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing items and equipment is accomplished by this maneuver, which can cover the following options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="list-style-position: inside;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draw, holster, ready, or load a weapon&lt;/strong&gt;. This maneuver covers the basic manipulations of most weapons, such as drawing a vibroknife from its sheath, recharging a blaster rifle&amp;#39;s energy cells (provided the character has additional ammo at hand—see page 181), or drawing and prepping a thermal detonator for use.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Draw something from storage, or put it away&lt;/strong&gt;. A character can perform a maneuver to retrieve an item from a pouch, backpack, satchel, bandolier, or some other accessible container. This can also be used to stow items in a similar fashion.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOUNT OR DISMOUNT &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mounting and dismounting a domesticated animal such as a trained dewback or a tauntaun requires a maneuver. (Successfully mounting an untrained animal, however, requires a Medium (2 difficulty dice) Survival check, which may be harder depending on how ornery the GM feels the animal is.) Similarly, mounting a vehicle, sliding into a cockpit, or otherwise engaging a vehicle for piloting or a gunnery station for use requires a maneuver as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This maneuver allows the character to move within his environment. The game defines several different broad types of movement. When characters move, they do one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style="list-style-position: inside;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change range increment&lt;/strong&gt;. Performing this maneuver allows a character to move between short and medium range relative to another person or object. This also allows characters to move between medium and long range by performing two maneuvers, or between long and extreme range by performing two maneuvers. When covering long distances, multiple maneuvers do not have to be performed on the same turn, but the character is not considered to be in the new range increment until all required maneuvers have been performed. For more detail on determining range, see Range Bands, page 208.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engage or Disengage from an opponent&lt;/strong&gt;. If a target is already within short range of a character, the character can perform a maneuver to engage that target. If the character is engaged with an opponent or adversary, he must perform a maneuver to disengage with that opponent before moving to any other location. This only changes his range relative to his opponent from &amp;#34;engaged&amp;#34; to &amp;#34;short&amp;#34; and represents the effort of backing away and avoiding his opponent&amp;#39;s attacks. Characters do not need to perform this maneuver to leave an engagement consisting only of friendly characters or allies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving within short range&lt;/strong&gt;. Performing this maneuver allows an unengaged character to move to another position that is currently within short range of him.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DROP PRONE OR STAND FROM PRONE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dropping prone and standing from a prone position each require a maneuver. Dropping prone allows the character to add 1 setback die to all ranged attacks made against him, although he also must add 1 boost die to all melee attacks made against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PREPARATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some actions require additional preparation to perform safely. The preparation maneuver is generally performed in conjunction with another ability to confer a bonus, offset a penalty, or fulfill a requirement. The individual talents or abilities that utilize the preparation maneuver define its specific effect. It is sometimes abbreviated under the requirements as &amp;#34;prepare.&amp;#34;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;&lt;/text&gt;
        &lt;topic&gt;General&lt;/topic&gt;
        &lt;use_count&gt;0&lt;/use_count&gt;
        &lt;valid_to&gt;2100-01-01&lt;/valid_to&gt;
        &lt;wiki/&gt;
        &lt;workflow_state&gt;published&lt;/workflow_state&gt;
    &lt;/kb_knowledge&gt;
    &lt;sys_translated_text action="delete_multiple" query="documentkey=a8c7ea532ff08590e0f497eef699b69c"/&gt;
&lt;/record_update&gt;
</payload>
        <sys_class_name>sys_metadata_link</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>ben.fisher</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2022-01-07 20:36:22</sys_created_on>
        <sys_customer_update>false</sys_customer_update>
        <sys_id>f488dbdb2f388590e0f497eef699b680</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>0</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>KB0010067</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Star Wars RPG" source="x_176383_star_wars">64b3517bdb5a08542901de90cf961993</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_replace_on_upgrade>false</sys_replace_on_upgrade>
        <sys_scope display_value="Star Wars RPG">64b3517bdb5a08542901de90cf961993</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>sys_metadata_link_f488dbdb2f388590e0f497eef699b680</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>ben.fisher</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2022-01-07 20:36:22</sys_updated_on>
        <tablename>kb_knowledge</tablename>
    </sys_metadata_link>
</record_update>
